Contact

iim.laitinen@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ilari-laitinen (LinkedIn) github.com/laitilari (Portfolio) ilari.pro/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Entrepreneurship Programming Scrum

Certifications

Cyber Security Base

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate

Honors-Awards

MSc (Tech) (Hons)

Ilari Laitinen

Software Engineer

Kauniainen

Summary

Software Engineer in Finland/remote.

4+ years of experience in agile software development.

Certified Microsoft Azure developer.

Aalto University MSc. (tech) honorary graduate.

Mainly doing full stack web development.

Most experienced in JavaScript and its frameworks.

Experience

Freelance
Software Engineer
August 2021 - Present (2 months)

Digitalent Finland
Senior Consultant
June 2021 - August 2021 (3 months)

Scrum Master | Azure DevOps | TypeScript | Puppeteer E2E tests

I excited this position to pursue a career as an independent consultant. I can recommend Digitalent with the utmost sincerety as an employer.

Tilastokeskus - Statistics Finland

1 year 11 months

Product Owner

January 2021 - June 2021 (6 months)

Previous position with added responsibility:

- QA
- Architecture
- Recruitment

Application Specialist

August 2019 - January 2021 (1 year 6 months)

Helsinki Area, Finland

Full-stack role in a scrum team responsible for building completely new Statistics Finland web services.

- We adopted DevOps and TDD processes.
- We moved from local infra to Azure cloud.
- We created infrastructure as code and CI/CD pipelines.
- We integrated with two different content management systems.
- We developed the back end of the new web service.
- We developed the front end of the new web service.
- We developed API's and Azure functions.
- We integrated data from old systems to new systems.

ES6+/JavaScript | Next.js | Python | Django | Azure | GraphQL | Scrum | TDD |
Cypress | Jasmine & Karma | SCSS | HTML | Contentful | GraphCMS

Freelance

Software Engineer September 2018 - August 2019 (1 year)

Consultant for Vediafi Oy:

- Full stack web developer in Vediafi Oy applications. React | Redux | Node |
 PostgreSQL | Python | SCSS
- Distributed ledger technology specialist in European Union's FEDeRATED project.
- Research participant and blockchain specialist in Ministry of Transport and Communications's project
 exploring readiness for digital transformation.

Web developer for Statistics Finland:

JavaScript | Web Components | Polymer | CSS

Tilastokeskus - Statistics Finland 1 year 3 months

Information Services Designer September 2017 - August 2018 (1 year) Helsinki Area, Finland

Front-end development.

- Automated statistical publishing.
- Integrated front end with API's.
- Programmed web applications for internal use.

Intern

June 2017 - August 2017 (3 months)

Helsinki Area, Finland

Designing and programming improvements to web services. Drafted and tested UI designs in live UX tests.

- Front-end development.
- Information services design.
- UI design.
- UX testing

PocketWings Oy

Founder

June 2015 - August 2017 (2 years 3 months)

Helsinki

- Co-founded a business
- Designed a product
- Manufactured products in China
- Managed an online shop
- Handled logistics and sales
- Partnered with Kiasma and Ateneum -museum shops as retailers

Helsingin Suomalainen Yhteiskoulu Substitute Teacher 2014 - May 2016 (2 years)

Helsinki

Teaching in high school and upper elementary school.

Education

Aalto University

Master's degree, Computer Science · (2018 - 2019)

University of Helsinki

Bachelor's Degree · (2014 - 2017)

Helsingin Suomalainen Yhteiskoulu

High School · (2010 - 2013)